#### **PADUA FIONA MURENZI**

Date of Birth: 26th January 1986

Nationality: Rwandan

Address: Kanombe, Kigali- Rwanda Present employer: King Faisal Hospital, Rwanda

Email: paduafiona@gmail.com

Phone: +250788721731/

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVES**

I am an organized and self-driven health professional with more than 10 years of experience in the health sector industry seeking an opportunity where I can further apply my professional experience and knowledge to drive positive change in my community and the world at large.

#### **AREAS OF FOCUS/STRENGTHS:**

- Over 10 years working experience in the healthcare industry and pharmaceutical industry in particular
- · Possess strong interpersonal, leadership and communication skills,
- Strong decision making and supervisory skills from years of serving in a managerial position
- Excellent networking abilities with stakeholders and clients from years with working with different stakeholders

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAININGS**

#### 2017-2018 Oklahoma Christian University

Oklahoma, USA

- Master of Business Administration (MBA) in Health care Management
- Graduated with a SUMA CUM LAUDE

## 2006-2009 University of the Western Cape, School of Pharmacy Cape Town, South Africa

- Bachelor of Pharmacy (B Pharm): Area of Focus; Pharmacology, Pharmaceutics,
  Pharmacy Practice and Pharmacy Laws
- Graduated on the Dean's Merit List for Academic Excellence

#### 2003-2004 Nabisunsa Girls High School

Kampala, Uganda

A Level Certificate

#### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS AND CAPABILITIES

I. **Areas of expertise;** Pharmacy, Business Administration, Procurement, Quality Improvement Audit Procurement,

#### **II. Short Professional Trainings and Courses**

- Certificate of Completion In Pharmaco-vigilance training of Trainers Karolinska Institutet in Association with the University of Rwanda
- Certificate of Merit for Trainers of Trainers in Drugs and Therapeutics Ministry of Health, Rwanda
- Certificate of Merit for training in Continuous Quality Improvement and Strategic Problem Solving
- Certificate of Merit for Trainers of Trainers in Strategic Problem Solving –Human Resource for Health
- E-Learning Course on Management in Health (Cohort 1) FY16 World Bank
- US abortion and FP requirements course- Global Health eLearning Center/ USAID
- HIV/AIDS Legal and Policy Requirements- Global Health eLearning Center/ USAID

#### III. Computer skills

- Microsoft office 2003, 2007 and 2010 program (Ms word, Ms Excel, Ms Power Point, Ms Outlook
- Pharmacy software: e-LMIS for pharmaceutical management

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Professional Experience**

June 2021 till present: Rwanda Foods and Drugs Authority

#### Position: Good Manufacturing Practice and Good Laboratory Practice Analyst

- Overall co-ordination of GMP inspection for premises used for the manufacture of pharmaceuticals; and Good distribution practice inspections for wholesale and retail pharmacies.
- Evaluation of GMP applications for manufacturing premises of pharmaceutical products
- Co-ordinate the development of guidelines, manuals, standard operating procedures (SOPs) and other quality management system documents for the division
- Implementation of the institution strategic and business plans to ensure achievemnets of the set performance targets

- Carry out GMP audits and provision of audit reports
- Maintenance of the GMP inspected premises register

#### March 2021-May 2021: USAID- Global Health Supply Chain/PSM under Chemonics

# (Left Position following Government of Rwanda appointment to join Rwanda Foods and Drugs Authority)

#### Position: Strategic Advisor to Rwanda Medical Supply

- Assisted the CEO to develop strategic interventions and advise the board of directors on the long-term sustainability of RMS Ltd operations.
- Provided technical assistance during the restructuring of RMS Ltd.
- Provided technical support and policy advices to the CEO of RMS Ltd
- Provided guidance in the elaboration of the RMS strategic plan, identified other strategies, and budget execution.
- To advise on the best management practices to be applied at the institution
- Reviewed the technical and administrative reports from RMS Ltd departments and created a clear system of reporting, Monitoring and Evaluation for the organization.
- Provide guidance on analysis of reports from departments to see if they are done in accordance with the targets fixed at the beginning of each fiscal year.
- I was in charge of guiding and advising the CEO on the regular monitoring, evaluation and benchmarking of the budget and Annual Operational plan based on the identified departmental indicators.
- Supported the RMS-CEO Office in building partnerships with donors such as USAID in mobilizing resources.

#### 2011 to February 2021: King Faisal Hospital

#### Positions: Pharmacist/ deputy-chief pharmacist/ Chief pharmacist / Director of Pharmacy

- Provided guidance on Good pharmaceutical practices in the hospital
- Monitored the Quality improvement practices and audits with regards to pharmaceuticals across the hospital
- Identified, created and reviewed necessary hospital guidelines, policies and procedures regarding pharmaceutical practices and medicines management.
- Carried out Drug utilization reviews

- Participate in strengthening of the hospital procurement processes by being a member of the Hospital Tender Board
- Promote evidence-based use of medicines and implementation of national guidelines
- Chairperson of the hospital pharmaco-vigiliance committee aimed at maintaining a system of reporting, and analysis of medicine incidents.
- Manage the pharmacy budget through the proper forecasting of needs and their prioritization
- Responsible for monitoring and reviewing drug administration clinical audits across the hospital
- Responsible for Planning and Compilation of the annual operational plan of the pharmacy
- Responsible for compiling the training needs of pharmacy staff, monitor the training outcomes and analyze the completeness of the yearly capacity building plan
- Carry out staff appraisals and identification of staff capacity development needs
- Identification of staffing needs for the department and make a business analysis supporting recruitment or maintenance of staff
- Reviewing and analysis of pharmacy performance reports to ensure our performance is inline in with our annual strategic targets
- Plan, quantify and procure government program pharmaceuticals (HIV, TB and Vaccines) through the ELMIS
- Taking part in the daily clinical rounds with the doctors

#### 2012 to 2019: King Faisal Hospital

#### **Chief Pharmacist**

- Oversee the management of medicine in the hospital
- Plan, quantify and procure Pharmaceuticals needed for running of the hospital
- Drive the medicines management committee and ensure organizational administrative support
- Promote evidence-based use of medicines and implementation of national guidelines through attendance of multi-disciplinary patient ward rounds
- Staff Scheduling by shifts and work assignment within the pharmacy department
- Deal with the day to day working issues of the department
- Organize and conduct meetings with internal staff

#### 2011 to 2012: King Faisal Hospital

#### **Deputy Chief- Pharmacist**

- Supervise day to day operations of the pharmacy
- Raise requests for needed stock-out medicinal products for the pharmacy
- In charge of compiling the pharmacy stores consumption report
- Planning of the quarterly stock taking process

#### Sep 2010 to 2011: King Faisal Hospital

#### Rwanda

#### **Pharmacist**

- Proper evaluation and dispensing of prescriptions
- Providing information on correct usage of medications as well as their possible side effects.
- Compounding of extemporaneous compounds.
- Dispensing over the counter medications
- Issuing and control of restricted medicinal product

#### Jan 2010 to Aug 2011: Netcare Blaauwberg Hospital

**South Africa** 

#### **Pharmacist Intern**

- Dispensing medicines under supervision of a registered pharmacist.
- Compounding of extemporaneous medication
- Participating in the stock counting process

#### 2007-2009: University of the Western Cape, School of Pharmacy South Africa

#### **Teaching Assistant**

- Explaining the principles of pharmacology
- Setting up and supervising weekly tutorials
- Grading the tutorial

### **LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY**

	COMPETENCY LEVELS		
LANGUAGE	SPEAK	READ	WRITE
ENGLISH	FLUENT	FLUENT	FLUENT
KINYARWANDA	FLUENT	FLUENT	FLUENT
FRENCH	GOOD WORKING KNOWLEDGE	GOOD WORKING KNOWLEDGE	GOOD WORKING KNOWLEDGE
SWAHILI	FLUENT	FLUENT	FLUENT

## **Other Professional Engagements**

- Registered with the Rwanda Pharmacy Council.
- Member of the Golden Key Honorary Society